torrens.edu.au 2017-12-12

# Privacy Policy | Torrens University

Every effort is made to ensure information on this website is up to date.

However, Torrens University Australia Limited does not give any warranty and accepts no responsibility for the accuracy or completeness of the material and reserves the right at any time to make changes as it deems appropriate.

Torrens University Australia Limited provides external links as a service to users of its website but does not accept responsibility for, or endorse the content or condition of, any linked site.

## Torrens University Australia Privacy Statement

**Introduction**

Torrens University Australia complies with the Privacy Act 1988 (Cwth) (Privacy Act) which protects the privacy of your personal information.

Read More

**Automatic Collection of Information**

The University automatically collects certain information when you visit our website, some of which may be capable of personally identifying you.

Read More

**Use of Cookies**

The University’s website uses cookies. A cookie is a text file placed on your computer to help analyse how users use a website.

Read More

**Personal Information**

Personal identifying information you supply whether on-line via online application forms, surveys, enquiries and email or over the phone or in hardcopy will be used by University staff in conducting the business of the University.

Read More

**Types of Personal Information**

The personal information the University collects and hold generally includes your name, address, date of birth, and contact details (such as your phone number and email address).

Read More

**Use of Personal Information  
**

The University uses the personal information you provide for a variety of reasons.

Read More

**Disclosure of Personal Information**

Information collected from you may be disclosed to third parties in limited circumstances expressly permitted in the Privacy Act, for example to State and Commonwealth Government Agencies as required or authorised by law.

Read More

**Information Involving Other Individuals**

During your communications with us you must not provide us with personal information ( including any sensitive information) of any other individual unless you have the express consent of that individual to do so.

Read More

**Security of Information**

The University takes reasonable steps (including any measure required by law) to ensure your personal information is protected from loss, misuse, interference and unauthorised access, alteration or disclosure.

Read More

**Public Forums**

Some University sites may have chat rooms, forums and message boards. Please remember that any information you disclose in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding whether to disclose your personal information.

Read More

**External Links  
**

Some University sites contain links to other sites. The University is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

Read More

**Accuracy, access and correction**

The University takes all reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information that it collects and hold is accurate, complete and up-to-date. However, the University relies on you to advise us of any changes to your personal information to help us maintain our records.

Read More

**Complaints**

If you wish to make a complaint about a breach of this Privacy Statement or the Privacy Act 1988(Cth) you can contact us using the contact details below. You will need to provide us with sufficient details regarding your complaint as well as any supporting evidence and/or information.

Read More

**Revisions to the Privacy Statement**

The University reserves the right to revise this Privacy Statement or any part of it from time to time. Please review this Privacy Statement periodically for changes.

Read More

### Introduction

Torrens University Australia complies with the Privacy Act 1988 (Cwth) (Privacy Act) which protects the privacy of your personal information. The purpose of this statement is to let you know what information is collected about you and how the information is used when you visit a Torrens University website, or provide your details directly to us, for example in person, over the phone, by email or by completing our online or hardcopy forms.

### Automatic Collection of Information

The University automatically collects certain information when you visit our website, some of which may be capable of personally identifying you. Such information includes the type of browser you are using, the type of operating system you are using, your IP address and how you use our website.

### Use of Cookies

The University’s website uses cookies. A cookie is a text file placed on your computer to help analyse how users use a website. A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, your IP address, the “lifetime” of the cookie, and a value (usually a randomly generated unique number). Cookies helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allow us to improve our website and services.

The University may use cookies in the following ways:

  * Where they are essential to make our website work
  * To enable the personalisation features on our website, and
  * To compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use our website and to help us improve the structure of our website. The University cannot identify you personally in this way.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. However, you may not be able to use all the interactive features of our website if cookies are disabled.

### Personal Information

Personal identifying information you supply whether on-line via online application forms, surveys, enquiries and email or over the phone or in hardcopy will be used by University staff in conducting the business of the University. Such uses include matters relating to student administration, provision of services to you, responding to your enquiries, and providing you with information about our courses and services.

### Types of Personal Information

The personal information the University collects and hold generally includes your name, address, date of birth, and contact details (such as your phone number and email address). With your express consent, the University may also collect and hold certain sensitive information relating to your racial or ethnic origins or your health for the purposes of providing services or assistance to you and to meet our reporting obligations to State and Australian Government agencies.

Your personal information, including sensitive information, will only be used for purposes consistent with the original purposes of collection. By law, you are not required to provide the University with your personal information. However, if you do not do so, you may not receive the full benefit of the complete range of services offered by the University.

### Use of Personal Information

The University uses the personal information you provide to:

  * Communicate with you and respond to your enquiries
  * Carry out day to day administrative matters
  * Inform you about events and activities relevant to your course, and other courses, services and opportunities that are available from the University and our affiliates
  * Maintain your academic record
  * Assist us in providing courses for the health and welfare of students
  * Keep alumni informed of events and opportunities that may be of interest to them through regular mailouts
  * Fulfil our State and Commonwealth Government reporting and statistical obligations
  * Assist in forecasting future needs of our products and services, and
  * Any other purposes identified at the time of collecting your information.

### Disclosure of Personal Information

Information collected from you may be disclosed to third parties in limited circumstances expressly permitted in the Privacy Act, for example to State and Commonwealth Government Agencies as required or authorised by law.

Personal information may also be disclosed to:

  * External organisations such as professional bodies, work-placement providers, and third parties engaged to act on behalf of the University
  * Other educational institutions in the Laureate International network (such as Laureate Education, Inc.) so that they can also offer you information and services (if you have opted-in to receive such information)
  * Our IT, infrastructure and operations service providers
  * Third-party providers of student services, and
  * Any other entities identified at the time of collecting your personal information.

Where personal information is to be provided to contractors or other external organisations, the University will require the recipient (and any contractor engaged by the recipient) to manage the information in a manner consistent with the Privacy Act.

Some personal information may be stored in the United States by a third-party provider of services to the University. This means that the information may not, in some circumstances, be regulated by Australian Privacy law. The University takes all reasonable steps in our contractual arrangements with overseas entities to ensure that they do not breach the Australian Privacy Principles in relation to personal information.

The transfer of your personal information to an overseas service provider may result in you being subject to a foreign law that could compel the disclosure of personal information to a third party, such as an overseas authority. At any time, you may withdraw your consent to the transfer of personal information to an overseas recipient by contacting the University’s Privacy Officer.

Other than as stated above the University will not share, rent, or sell your personal information. If there are other situations in which the University wishes to use your personal information, it will seek your express consent.

### Information Involving Other Individuals

During your communications with us you must not provide us with personal information (including any sensitive information) of any other individual unless you have the express consent of that individual to do so.

If you do provide us with such information about another individual, you:

  * Must tell that individual that you will be providing their information to the University and that the University will handle their information in accordance with the University’s Privacy Policy
  * Must provide that individual with a copy of (or refer them to) this Privacy Statement, and
  * Warrant that you have that individual’s consent to provide their information to us.

### Security of Information

The University takes reasonable steps (including any measure required by law) to ensure your personal information is protected from loss, misuse, interference and unauthorised access, alteration or disclosure.

However, data protection and security measures are never completely secure and, despite the measures the University has put in place, the University cannot guarantee the security of your information. You must take care to ensure you protect your personal information (for example, by protecting any usernames and passwords, etc.) and you should notify us as soon as possible after you become aware of any security breaches.

### Public Forums

Some University sites may have chat rooms, forums and message boards. Please remember that any information you disclose in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding whether to disclose your personal information.

### External Links

Some University sites contain links to other sites. The University is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

### Accuracy, Access and Correction

The University takes all reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information that it collects and hold is accurate, complete and up-to-date. However, the University relies on you to advise us of any changes to your personal information to help us maintain our records.

The University will, on request, provide you with access to the personal information it holds about you unless otherwise required by law. The University will notify you of the basis for any denial of access your personal information.

To request access to your personal information or, if you wish to update or correct your personal information, please contact us via the contact details provided below.

### Complaints

If you wish to make a complaint about a breach of this Privacy Statement or the Privacy Act 1988(Cth) you can contact us using the contact details below. You will need to provide us with sufficient details regarding your complaint as well as any supporting evidence and/or information.

The University will refer your complaint to our Privacy Officer who will investigate the issue and determine the steps (if any) that the University will undertake to resolve your complaint. The University will contact you if it requires any additional information from you and will notify you in writing of the outcome of the investigation. If you are not satisfied with the University’s determination, you can contact the University to discuss your concerns or complain to the Australian Privacy Commissioner via [www.oaic.gov.au. ](http://www.oaic.gov.au./)

### Revisions to the Privacy Statement

The University reserves the right to revise this Privacy Statement or any part of it from time to time. Please review this Privacy Statement periodically for changes. If the University makes material changes to this Privacy Statement, it will notify you by email or by putting a notice on the Torrens University Australia website.

Your continued use of our website, services or provision of further personal information to us once you have been notified of the revised Privacy Statement constitutes your deemed acceptance of the revised Privacy Statement.

### Contact us

All privacy enquiries and complaints should be directed in writing to the Privacy Officer using the [Access to Personal Information form](https://laureate-au.blackboard.com/bbcswebdav/xid-7823931_1). Torrens University will respond to a complaint within a reasonable period of time. The contact details for Torrens University are:

Privacy Officer  
Torrens University Australia  
Level 24, 680 George Street  
Sydney NSW 2000
